## Ashwani Kumar V

Senior DevOps Engineer

- **\( +91 7989 121 975**
- ✓ avardhineni7@gmail.com
- ♥ Hyderabad, IN
- in linkedin.com/in/avk-sd
- github.com/SimplifiedDevOps

#### **SUMMARY**

9+ years of experience in IT field which includes 6+ years in handling AWS Cloud environments, Build and Administer Micro-Services architecture through K8S & AWS EKS.

Proficiency in working in DevOps lifecycle management environment, creating build & release pipelines, Infrastructure Automation & Configuration Management in multiple environments.

Analytical, committed, persistent individual and reliable team member. Continuously learning and acquiring new knowledge and skills.

## **KEY SKILLS**

Linux System Administration Bash, Python Scripting **AWS Cloud** AWS Security, DevSecOps **Terraform** Ansible, Packer Git/Git Hub, Bitbucket, Code Commit Maven, JFrog, Sonarqube Nginx, Apache Tomcat Jenkins, CodeBuild Docker, CodeDeploy Kubernetes, AWS EKS Helm Charts, CodePipeline Prometheus & Grafana CloudWatch AWS Lambda, API Gateway JIRA

# AWS Cloud Administration, Terraform & Ansible Automation, Kubernetes Admin with DevOps Lifecycle

## **Professional Experience**

Senior Cloud Engineer, Visionet Systems Pvt. Ltd. Bengaluru
Date: July 2021 – Till date
Job Profile: Build and Release Management, Deployment Automation, and Kubernetes Administration.

**Cloud Engineer, TCS, Hyderabad** 

Payroll: Ivytel Technologies Pvt. Ltd. Bengaluru,

Date: January 2018 - July 2021

Job Profile: AWS Administration & DevOps Engineer

Module Lead, Mindtree LTD. Hyderabad, Date: February 2015 – December 2017

Job Profile: AWS Administration & Infrastructure Automation

#### **Employment History**

## **Roles and Responsibilities**

- Collaborate with software ,product ,development, architecture and IT teams to ensure releases are delivered with repeatable and auditable processes.
- Responsible for application Build & Release process which includes Code Compilation, Packaging, Security Scanning and code quality scanning, Deployment Methodology and Application Configurations.
- 3. Architect and design the setup and configuration of CI/CD pipelines and support/resolve technical complexities to integrate various DevOps practices as part of CI/CD implementation.
- 4. Work closely with product teams to find the right trade-off between business-specific needs and state-of-the-art CI/CD best practices.
- 5. Build and maintain tools for **deployment**, **monitoring**, and **operations**.
- Execute and automate operational processes quickly, accurately, and securely. Provide solutions to increase visualization, reduce errors, and improve customer experience.
- 7. **Support and troubleshoot scalability, high availability**, performance, monitoring, **backup, and restoration** of different environments.
- 8. Troubleshoot and **resolve issues in Development,** Test, and **Production** environments.
- 9. Evaluate **new tools, technologies, and processe**s to improve the speed, efficiency, and **scalability of continuous integration** environments.
- 10. Used Jira as a Change Management/ Work Management/ Scrum Agile Tool. Updating the application team in order to track the status of the user stories or defects.

## Skills and Experience

- 1. Embedding **Security** at every step of **SDLC** with various **DevSecOps tools**.
- Expertise in deploying at scale various containerized web, data applications, and services using Docker, Kubernetes, Elastic Kubernetes Service (EKS), Elastic Container Service (ECS), CloudWatch, and other monitoring solutions.
- 3. Strong experience in **40+ AWS services** such as EC2, ELB ALB & NLB, ASG, IAM, CloudWatch, Relational Database Service (RDS), S3, etc.

## **DevSecOps Tools**

Git Hooks & Talisman Mutation Tests - PIT SonarQube

Trivy Image Scan

**OPA Confest** 

KubeSec

DAST

**OWASAP ZAP** 

CIS Benchmarking & Kube-Bench

Istio

Kiali

Falco

KubeScan

HashiCorp Vault

### **EDUCATION**

**Education History** 

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

AWS Certified Solutions Architect -Associate Hashicorp Certified - Terraform Associate

- 4. Configured **AWS Security Services** such as IAM, KMS, ACM, WAF, Inspector, Trusted Advisor, Cloud Trail, Config, and Guard Duty to **secure resources** at multiple layers.
- 5. Used **Terraform to build** multiple environments such as Dev, Staging and Prod using AWS DevOps workflow.
- 6. Standardized the **Terraform modules** for all the resources in AWS Cloud. This helped in **reducing the code time** and re-usability of the modules.
- 7. Automated the **creation of Golden AMI** through **Packer** and used **Ansible** for **Application configuration**.
- 8. Extensively **used Ansible** to **install and configure** all the **DevOps tools**. Also **Dynamically** configured the **inventory file** to avoid manual input of IP address in the host file.
- 9. Used Jenkins Pipelines to drive all Micro Services builds out to the Docker/ECR registry and then deployed to Kubernetes/ECS/EKS, and managed the application with various Kubernetes Objects also integrated with Jira and Slack to send build state information.
- 10. **Optimize Jenkins container configurations** such as mount docker runtime inside **container as a volume**, fixing permissions on docker.sock, and **scripted Jenkins configurations** in to a Jenkinsfile to run **Single Pipeline** and **MultiBranch** Pipeline Jobs.
- 11. Experience in administrating Kubernetes and a good understanding of manifest management with Helm along with expertise in Ingress Controller and Service mesh with Istio for pod communication and encryption.
- 12. Used **Terraform to automate** the EKS Cluster and integrated Terraform in **CI/CD Pipelines** to automate provisioning of Servers.
- 13. Automated tasks such as System Checks, Monitoring and Remote Administration, Backup and Restore, Scheduled tasks, Clean-up, Data Visualizations, Send Notifications, CI/CD related tasks through Python Scripting.
- 14. Expert in configuring & operating **ELK/EFK ElasticStack** for deep search and data analytics, **fluentD** for centralized logging, log enrichment and parsing and **Kibana for powerful** and beautiful data visualizations.
- 15. Used **Jira as change Management** and **Scrum Agile** tool. Updating the applications team in order to track the status of the **user stories/defects**.
- 16. Configured **Prometheus Server** and its **components such as** Grafana, Alertmanager, ServiceMonitor, Prometheus Rules to monitor all Cluster Nodes, K8S Components, Microservices Applications and Redis Data broker.
- 17. Successfully **upgraded the Kubernetes and Jenkins** by following the best practices and Effectively took the **back up of ETCD** database and performed timely **restore drills**.
- 18. Performed **Cost optimization with Kubecost** to avoid overspending on the resources.

## **Looking Forward To Learn**

- 1. Azure Cloud, Azure DevOps
- 2. GCP
- 3. CKA Certification
- 4. New DevOps and DevSecOps tools that emerge during my DevOps Engineer Journey.